<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="en">
	<title>glennabaron.com</title>
	<subtitle>.</subtitle>
	<link href="https://glennabaron.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://glennabaron.com/"/>
	<updated>2018-07-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://glennabaron.com/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Glenna Baron</name>
		<email>baronglenna@gmail.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Five Neat Things: Rest</title>
		<link href="https://glennabaron.com/blog/2018-07-08-rest/"/>
		<updated>2018-07-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://glennabaron.com/blog/2018-07-08-rest/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I took a few days off work last week, I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Rest-More-Done-When-Work/dp/0465074871&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rest: Why You Get More Done When You Work Less&lt;/a&gt;. My mind is brimming with ideas about mandatory time off, exercise, and sabbaticals. One of the ideas that stuck with me is about stopping your work while you still know what you are doing, not when you get stuck, or have everything wrapped up. The book suggests this allows you brain to keep thinking on the subject and for ideas to come more easily the next time you sit down to work. Highly recommended!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all the talk surrounding banning plastic straws, here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/06/disposable-america/563204/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;history lesson&lt;/a&gt; on them. It makes me wonder, who is making all these every day, “boring” products we don’t spend much time thinking about? What is innovation like at those companies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are memes for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2018/jul/05/meet-the-numtots-the-millennials-who-find-fixing-public-transit-sexy-urbanist-memes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;everything&lt;/a&gt;. These public transit ones are both silly and inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…the intention was to make silly jokes – but it’s morphed into this thing where people feel inspired by the group, directly or indirectly, to go into urban planning and policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/were-all-out-of-touch/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;We’re All Innocently Out of Touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realizing how many different views exist forces you into one of two spots: Arguing with others whose views you think are wrong, or realizing how out of touch you are with people whose experiences have led them to different views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My thoughts have come back to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raptitude.com/2018/05/where-success-leaks/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; many times in the few weeks since I read it. It talks about the small things we keep doing that prevent us from truly becoming great, and can be applied to so many things in life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are your chronic amateur mistakes? Think about where you’ve been stagnant, and ask yourself what you do that the pros would never allow themselves to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Five Neat Things: Tapped Out</title>
		<link href="https://glennabaron.com/blog/2018-06-16-tapped-out/"/>
		<updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://glennabaron.com/blog/2018-06-16-tapped-out/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been &lt;s&gt;busy&lt;/s&gt;, ahem, prioritizing other things lately. I’ve also felt like I’ve been in a bit of a rut, and not in the mood to read and consume. Jocelyn said it best in her &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchi.mp/jkglei/5kpdgbptbz-998993?e=395624e4a8&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; from the other week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But lately, I’ve been a little tapped out on consuming other people’s content. I’m knee-deep in working on two new creative projects, and &lt;strong&gt;it’s hard to hear your own voice if you’re constantly cramming other people’s ideas into your brain&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally felt the urge to put a few links together, so here’s a couple neat things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loved looking through &lt;a href=&quot;https://kottke.org/18/05/hundreds-of-amazing-1980s-tech-company-logos&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;these logos&lt;/a&gt;. Makes me think about all the small tech companies of the past that didn’t “make it” (a la &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halt_and_Catch_Fire_(TV_series)&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Halt and Catch Fire&lt;/a&gt;). Also reminds me that its been too long since I stretched my design muscles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can’t wait for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Doesnt-Have-Be-Crazy-Work-ebook/dp/B079WV79TK/ref=tmm_kin_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1527893404&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breakthetwitch.com/getting-back-to-happy/&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;On resistance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2018/06/in-praise-of-extreme-moderation&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In praise of extreme moderation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I long ago decided to invest in extreme moderation. I do everything with the deliberate intent of finding a balance between two extremes — doing nothing and doing too much. I want to do a reasonable job at the different parts of my life and a stellar job at the balance between all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/06/the-unbearable-awkwardness-of-automation/562670/&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;On architecture and automation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Five Neat Things: Making Progress</title>
		<link href="https://glennabaron.com/blog/2018-03-25-making-progress/"/>
		<updated>2018-03-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://glennabaron.com/blog/2018-03-25-making-progress/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most straightforward explanation I’ve read about what’s gone on with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/opinion/facebook-cambridge-analytica.html&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Facebook and Cambridge Analytica&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cait and Carrie’s podcast, straightforwardly titled “&lt;a href=&quot;https://honestmoneypodcast.com&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Honest Money Conversations&lt;/a&gt;“, is one of my favorites. One of their latest episodes on &lt;a href=&quot;https://honestmoneypodcast.com/consuming-mindfully&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;consuming mindfully&lt;/a&gt; reminded me that it&#39;s impossible to stay up to date on well, everything. I&#39;ve tried to cut back the amount I was saving and reading online the past few weeks, which explains why this post is &amp;quot;late&amp;quot; (I told myself I would do a &amp;quot;neat things&amp;quot; post every week).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that note, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/i-am-the-very-important-longread-everyone-is-talking-about&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Very Important Longread Everyone is Talking About&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was part of the same Hurry Slowly podcast I mentioned last week, but I can’t stop thinking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hofstadter%27s_law&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hofstadter’s Law&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It always takes longer than you expect, even when you take into account Hofstadter&#39;s Law.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which reminds me of habits. I finally have a meditation practice down, which I struggled with for all of 2017. The latest habit I’ve been trying to form has been to drink 20oz of water upon waking up. Part of it is remembering to put the bottle of water on my nightstand the night before. Part of it is making sure I don’t get stuck looking at my phone for the first 15 minutes of my day. But I’ve gotten progressively better at doing this. I have to remind myself that it always takes a while to make something stick, usually longer than you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I wrapped up David Chang’s new series on Netflix, “Ugly Delicious”. In one of the episodes, Dave chats with actress Gillian Jacobs about what it was like starting out in the restaurant and acting industries, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GJ [on acting]: “…when you first start, its completely overwhelming, you’re fucking up all the time, you’re getting yelled at, and then at a certain point maybe you can go on autopilot…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DC [on being a chef]: “…you can, and thats where you get into trouble, if you’re not nervous or nauseous every day, then you’re going to regress.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their conversation really stuck with me this past week, and can be applied to how it feels to start, or restart, anything you’re passionate about. More on the series &lt;a href=&quot;https://longreads.com/2018/03/22/david-changs-ugly-delicious-pushes-food-tv-in-the-right-direction&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Five Neat Things: Starting Small</title>
		<link href="https://glennabaron.com/blog/2018-03-11-starting-small/"/>
		<updated>2018-03-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://glennabaron.com/blog/2018-03-11-starting-small/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been putting this off for a while now. For months I have been telling myself I need to update my website, start sharing the interesting things I read, and generally put all the thoughts bouncing around my head into super smart and introspective words. But the bigness of it all has held me back. I want it to be perfect! And put together! And please everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have drafts of posts scattered about on multiple note-taking apps, incomplete fragments of thoughts jotted down within physical notebooks, and dozens of uncommited files. I&#39;ve spent many hours attempting to find the perfect solution to organizing everything that I have read and everything I plan to read. It started to become too overwhelming, and while I was spending entire weekends reading, I wasn&#39;t giving myself enough time to process what I had read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While searching around trying to solve a problem at work (&lt;a href=&quot;https://vgpena.github.io/winning-with-css-variables/&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fallbacks for css variables&lt;/a&gt;), I stumbled across &lt;a href=&quot;https://vgpena.github.io/good-is-better-than-perfect/&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article that really pushed me to &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; hit publish. Maybe these thoughts are incomplete, and hell, the code isn&#39;t even perfect. But I expect this to grow and evolve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, here are five neat things I found this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to Edward Tufte&#39;s work in college and I was thrilled to find out he offers one day &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edwardtufte.com/tufte/courses&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt;. How cool would it be to go to one of these?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jocelyn Glei&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://hurryslowly.co/&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hurry Slowly&lt;/a&gt; has undoubtedly become my favorite podcast. This week&#39;s episode on &lt;a href=&quot;http://hurryslowly.co/020-jocelyn-k-glei&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;maintenance&lt;/a&gt; sparked so many ideas that can be applied to any discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@pnowelldesign/different-design-process-different-result-aec654c1f91c&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;design process&lt;/a&gt;. I recently left the agency world, where I was starting to feel like the web design process was becoming very rigid and controlled. Maybe building a website can be exciting again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know how to make a website; that’s not the concern. But if we want something truly unique, we need to first discover what that is and not assume that the same-old web design process is going to yield a different result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you do anything &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fs.blog/2013/10/what-you-do-today-is-not-essential/&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;essential&lt;/a&gt; today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And my favorite read of the week, &lt;a href=&quot;https://abe-winter.github.io/plea&#39;s/help/2018/02/11/slack.html&quot; :target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Slack is the opposite of organizational memory&lt;/a&gt;. I have since turned off my “is typing” feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slack is inherently rushed: I feel like I’m in a hurry to whisper before someone shouts. [...] Paradoxically, speed is just as toxic to group thought, as people will race to get out ideas and leave them half-formed or contradictory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are people blind to this? I think because most people never understood how work gets done or don’t think about it. Now slack comes in and makes ‘work’ visible in the form of instant replies to quick questions, dancing emoji stickers, and nonstop chatter, and some people are like, ‘yes! look at all that my team has accomplished’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Down with interruptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
